Carlos Fernando Pinzón J.

Floridablanca, Colombia · linkedin.com/in/carlosfpj · +57 315 49 21108 · cafer89@gmail.com

Chemical Engineer with over 8 years of experience as a Process Engineer in the Oil & Gas industry. I lead process engineering projects for clients such as Ecopetrol, ODL, and CENIT, among others. I have worked on projects in Ecuador and Colombia, delivering solutions that enhance the operational efficiency of production fields. My international perspective and adaptability to diverse environments allow me to provide innovative solutions and add value to multidisciplinary teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SeringtecProcess Engineer

Floridablanca, Colombia

June 2024–Present

- Conceptual, basic, and detailed engineering for production water handling facilities in the Rubiales field.
- Detailed engineering for water management at the ODL station.
- Engineering for crude oil pumping facilities at the CENIT station.
- Lead the development of process engineering documents, simulations, calculation reports, drawings, and philosophies for clients.
- Contribution to risk workshops, including HAZOP, HAZID, and WHAT-IF studies.
- Optimized process engineering deliverables for the ODL client, reducing process discipline man-hours by 10% for the project.
- Consistently integrate engineering developments with other disciplines to ensure a complete and cohesive product.
- Implementation of variable power consumption equipment for energy efficiency.

Consorcio Integridad VRC

Process Engineer

Barrancabermeja, Colombia

January 2023-June 2024

- Technical support in the development of change control engineering for the Mares and Ríos management areas of the Central Regional Vice Presidency (VRC) Ecopetrol.
- Development of drawings, simulations, calculations, and process engineering documents.
- Identified opportunities for operational process improvements, achieving a 10% increase in the efficiency of rotating equipment in the Provincia field.

CPM - HERON

Quito, Ecuador

Junior Process Engineer

March 2018–Dec 2022

- Making of process engineering documents, construction supervision, material procurement, field adjustments, boiler operation, and commissioning of the production plant.
- Training of operations personnel for PetroEcuador.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD AUTÓNOMA DE BUCARAMANGA

Specialist in Energy Resources Management

Bucaramanga, Colombia

Sep 2017

UNIVERSIDAD INDUSTRIAL DE SANTANDER

Chemical Engineer

Bucaramanga, Colombia Sep 2015

LANGUAGES

• Spanish, English.